Guide to the William W. Renwick papers, 1792-1948 (bulk 1840-1927) RL.11836
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
William W. Renwick papers
1792-1948 (bulk 1840-1927)
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Renwick, William W., 1811-1872
RL.11836
2393 items
William W. Renwick was an enslaver and cotton planter from Newberry and Union counties, S.C. Collection includes correspondence and other papers of Renwick, his wife, Rosannah Rogers Renwick, and related members of the Beard, Bothwell, Lyons, Renwick, and Rogers families, including material on South Carolina cotton planting, slavery, politics, social life, and customs; U.S. Representative James Rogers; and the Renwick and Rogers families.
Biographical / Historical
William W. Renwick was an enslaver and cotton planter from Newberry and Union counties, S.C.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The William W. Renwick papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1950 and 1951.
Collection Overview
Collection includes correspondence and other papers of Renwick, his wife, Rosannah Rogers Renwick, and related members of the Beard, Bothwell, Lyons, Renwick, and Rogers families, including material on South Carolina cotton planting, slavery, politics, social life, and customs; U.S. Representative James Rogers; and the Renwick and Rogers families.
Related Materials
William W. Renwick Papers, South Caroliniana Library, University of South Carolina.
John and William W. Renwick Papers, Georgia Historical Society.
Cotton growing -- South Carolina; Slavery -- United States; South Carolina -- Politics and government; South Carolina -- Social life and customs; Beard family.; Bouthwell family.; Lyons family.; Renwick family.; Rogers family; Renwick, Rosannah Rogers, 1812-1850; Rogers, James, 1795-1873
- Papers, 1792-1849 (Box 1)
- Papers, 1850-1869 (Box 2)
- Papers, 1870-1885 (Box 3)
- Papers, 1886-1920 (Box 5)
- Papers, 1921-1948 (Box 4)
- Papers (Box 6)
- Papers (Box 7)
- Bound volumes (Box 7)
- Renwick and Rice sawmill account book, 1857-1859 (Volume F: 6752)
  Scope and Contents
  Newberry, South Carolina, 152 pages.
- James E. Renwick physician's daybook, 1874-1878 (Volume S: 5880)
  Orange Hall, Union County, South Carolina, 107 pages.
- James E. Renwick physician's daybook, 1880 (Volume M: 5881)
  Orange Hall, Union County, South Carolina, 73 pages.
- James E. Renwick notebook, 1875 (Volume M: 5882)
  Notes on medical lectures delivered in Charleston, 150 pages.